So, if you're going to fence competitively, in a USFA competition, that holds true in the United States, there are some regulations that differ in Europe and other countries, but for USFA this is everything you're going to need.
First, one mask.
The mask has to pass FIE regulations; that means that first of all the bib has to be sewn in, you can't have a snap in bib and it also has to sustain a certain amount of pressure, I think its 12 kilograms.
If it doesn't sustain a certain amount of pressure when it's being tested at the competition it doesn't matter if it actually is FIE it still doesn't fly.
So it's not a bad idea to have a spare helmet along with you.
Next you need two electric weapons.
I have two Epee's here, if you're fencing foil, obviously you're going to need two electric foils that are in good working order.
You bring two because, of course, nothing is foolproof, and electric weapons, like everything else, on occasion, do occasionally fail.
Next, two working body cords.
For the same reason, bring two with you.
Of course, your jacket.
Your jacket has no minimum regulations as far as how many newtons it needs to have.
But it does have to have a strap at the bottom; that used to be optional; it's not anymore, you need this handy strap.
Glove - you need one glove.
You might want two gloves.
There are gloves that have Velcro cuffs that allow the body cord to pass through, so that's not a bad idea.
Again, you want to size your glove properly before ordering.
Your Lame; a Lame in good working order that's going to pass a test.
You need that for foil, you also need a sabre one for a sabre.
Your Plastron; you're required extra underarm protection.
And also if you're a woman your added chest plate added protection.
If you're a man, you need that cup, not that cup, but the right cup.
And other optional equipment is your chest plate for a man.
In addition to these items, you need a pair of pants; they have to be white.
They have to pass the 4-inch overlap rule.
You need a pair of socks; they have to come up to your shin, they have to come up to your pants.
You need a pair of shoes.
You want them to be good and comfortable and to assist you in your athletic endeavors.
And I think that might just be enough.